Education and Jewish Education 0007.023.005
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
Education and Jewish Education
1963-2012
0007.023.005
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
3.5 Cubic feet 5 boxes and 2 box of photographs.
The Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford holds a small amount of material related to education of local Jewish students in the public schools and in institutions of higher learning. The society has greater holdings related specifically to Jewish educations that are described below. Public school education at the elementary and secondary level is also included here. The Jewish Education collection consists of material related to the many schools of Jewish education that have existed in Greater Hartford. Most of the material relates to secondary level programs. The collection also contains material related to issues related to Jewish education both locally and nationally Midrasha was established in 1963 as a Conservative supplemental after-school program for high school students. In 1970 Midrasha expanded its programs to include students from both Reform and Orthodox congregations as well as young people from unaffiliated families. Later, eighth graders were included when it became apparent that Jewish teenagers needed a program to bridge the gap between their Bar/Bat Mitzvah in seventh grade and high school. Midrasha merged with Beit No'ar in 1995 to form Yachad. Yachad (Greater Hartford Jewish Community High School) was founded in 1995 as a successor to Midrasha and Bet No'ar. Yachad provides an enrichment after-school Jewish experience to students from all branches of Judaism. Unlike Midrasha, Yachad offers time-limited studies and concentrates on recreation as well as academics. The Yachad program offers activities in art, music, theater, travel, student government and mitzvah programs. Hebrew High School of New England (HHNE) was founded in 1996 to provide secondary Jewish Education to students in the Springfield, Massachusetts, Hartford and New Haven regions. Although primarily Modern Orthodox in orientation, HHNE is open to all Jewish students. The school offers a coed secular curriculum and single-sex programs for Judaic education. HHNE's academic standards are demanding and rigorous in all subjects. The school was formerly housed in the education building of the Agudas Achim Synagogue. The HHNE moved into the permanent Grinspoon-Konover Building on Bloomfield Avenue in West Hartford, opening on January 3rd, 2011.
Photographs
Most of the photographs in this collection are of Midrasha graduations. There are also some older photographs of early Jewish Education programs.
Box 1: A-M
Adult Education/Hebrew Institute for Jewish Studies, 1958
Arsenal School, c.1900
Barnard, Henry School
Brown Street School Annex, 1911
Bulkeley High School, early 20th
Harris, Chauncy School OVERSIZE
Hartford Hebrew School: see Talmud Torah
Hartford Public High School, 1905
Hartford Public High School, early 20th. See also oversize
Hartford Public High School/clubs, early 20th
Hartford Public High School/Athena Debating Club, c. 1920
Hartford Public High School/Orchestra, early 20th
Hartford Public High School/Sports, early 20th
Hartfrod Public High School/OVERSIZE education photos, several, early 20th/sports/debating
Hartford Talmud Torah, 1903/Rabbie David Traub's Cheder/Nettie Finkelstein, (Mrs. Samuel L. Goldman) only girl
Hartford Yeshiva/Hebrew Academy
Hartford Yeshiva/Hebrew Academy/builidngs
Hartford Yeshiva/Hebrew Academy/buildings/Gaster plaque dedication, 1992
Jones Junior High School, 1940s SUPER OVERSIZE. Copy
Jones Junior High School, 1940s
Maccabean Sunday School, 1918
Midrasha: filed here under M. Folders are labeled "Jewish Education/High Schools/Midrasha"
High Schools/Midrasha/Scholarships/Annie Fisher
High Schools/Midrasha/Activities, 1980s
High Schools/Midrasha/Choral Group, 1968-1969
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1968
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1969
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1970
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1971
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1972
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1973
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1974
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1975
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1976
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1977
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1978
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1979
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1980
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1981
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1983
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1984
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1986
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1988
High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation/Display of work, 1971
High Schools/Midrasha/Holocaust Commemorations
High Schools/Midrasha/Jewish Art Classes, 1968-1969
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous, 1980s
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous, 1987
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous, 1990s
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Activities/Polaroid's
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Contact Sheets, 1980s
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Polaroid's, 1980s
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Polaroids, 1980s
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Slides, 1980s
High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Students
High Schools/Midrasha/Students, 1980s
Miscellaneous Suburban Schools, 1915
Nelson Street Talmud Torah, 1934
New Britain Talmud Torah, c.1910
Second North District School Plaque
Northeast Ladies Talmud Torah: see Nelson Street Talmud Torah
Northeast School, 1920s
Box 2: N-Z
Northwest School, 1920s, 1940s
Pleasant Street Talmud Torah, 1914. The School was also known as Hartford Hebrew School.
Public Schools/Norwich/Ableman, Beatrice Evelyn
Second North District School
Solomon Schechter Day School/building, 1985
Solomon Schechter Day School/Board, 1990s
Solomon Schechter Day School/Students and activities
Taslitt's Hebrew School, 1930s
Second North School/Henry Barnard School, 1912
Trinity College, 1920s
United Conservative Religious School, 1980s
UConn Alumni
Vine Street school: see also Weaver High School1941
Wadsworth School OVERSIZE
Weaver High School, reunion of class of 1948 in 1982
Weaver High School 35th reunion, class of 1940 in 1975
Weaver High School, 1941: Seymour Gold, Edwin Stolz, Dick Berenson, ? Winnick, Bob Yellin, see also Vine Street School
Weaver High School/class of 1932 50th reunion, 1982 OVERSIZE
Oversized Materials:
Arsenal School
Brown School
Brown Street School Annex
Hartford Hebrew School
Hartford Public High School (both building and students)
Hebrew Academy
Northwest School
Norwich
Taslitt's Hebrew School
Arsenal School; Barnard-Brown Schools; Beit Midrash; Central Connecticut State University; Connecticut College; Connecticut State Agricultural College; Frank O. Jones Junior High School; Hall High School; Hartford College for Women; Hartford Hillel; Hartford Institute for Jewish Studies; Hartford Seminary; Hebrew High School of New England; Hebrew Union College; Hebrew University; Jewish Theological Seminary; Kadima High School / Beit Safer Tichon; Midrasha; Miss Porter's School; Northeast School; Northwest School; Talmud Torah; Trinity College; University of Connecticut (UCONN); Vine Street School; Weaver High School; West Middle School; Yachad (Greater Hartford Community High School)
- Series I: High Schools/Beit Noar; Midrasha, A-Board of Directors/Minutes 1970s
  - Beit Noar, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/By-laws, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/By-laws/Drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Committees, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Committees/Education, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Committees/Education/Committee Records, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Committees/Executive, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Incorporation, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Members, undated (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Minutes, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Minutes, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Series II: High Schools/Midrasha, Board of Directors/Minutes 1980s-Financial/Budget, 1980
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Minutes, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Minutes, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Presidents/Wagner, Jerry/Correspondence, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Board of Directors/Principals/Weiner, Ruth, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Building, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Calendar, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Correspondence/Parents, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Correspondence/Rabbis and Synagogues, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Correspondence/Students, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Curriculum, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Curriculum, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Curriculum, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Curriculum, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Curriculum, n.d., undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Curriculum/Two-track system, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Events, undated (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Budget, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Budget, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 2)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Budget, 1979-1980, 1979-1989 (Box 2)
- Series III: High Schools/Midrasha, Financial/Budget, 1981-G
  - Midrasha/Financial/Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Budget, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Jewish Federation/Allocation, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Jewish Federation/Incentive Grants, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Jewish Federation/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Tax exempt status, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Financial/Tuition, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Fundraising/, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Graduations/Speeches, undated (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Graduations/Programs, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Graduations/Programs, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Graduations/Programs, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 3)
  - Midrasha/Graduations/Programs, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 3)
  - Series VI: High Schools/Yachad; Hebrew High School of New England (HHNE)
    - Yachad/Board of Directors, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Curriculum and Activities, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Financial, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Financial/Endowment Foundation Grants, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Fundraising, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Newspaper clippings, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Newspaper clippings, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Program catalogs, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Publicity, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Reports, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Strategic Planning, undated (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Teen Philanthropy Institute, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 6)
    - Yachad/Teen Philanthropy Institute/Legacy Project Interviews, November 2009 (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Admissions, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Board of Directors/By-laws, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Board of Directors/Members, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Calendar, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Community service projects, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Curriculum, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Events, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Financial/Jewish Federation, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Founding, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Fundraising, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Graduation, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Newsletters, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Newsletters/Student, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Principal, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Publicity, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Strategic Planning, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Student Handbook, undated (Box 6)
    - HHNE/Yearbook, undated (Box 6)
- Series IV: High Schools/Midrasha, H-R
  - Midrasha/History, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Holocaust-related programs, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Israel related programs, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Junior Midrasha, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Library, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Newsletters, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Newsletters/Parents, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Newspaper clippings, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Newspaper clippings, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Newspaper clippings, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Newspaper clippings, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Publicity/Advertisements, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Publicity/Press Releases, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Publicity/Promotional Brochures, undated (Box 4)
  - Midrasha/Registration and recruitment, undated (Box 4)
- Series V: High Schools/Midrasha, S-Z
  - Midrasha/Scholarships, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Scholarships/Jewish Children's Service Organization, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Solomon Schechter Day School, support for, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Staff, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Staff/Directors, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Staff/Directors/Cohen-Kiener, Andrea/Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Staff/Directors/Markowitz, Israel/Correspondence, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Staff/Reports, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Strategic Planning, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Strategic Planning/Survey, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Students/lists, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Students/lists, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Students/lists, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Students/lists, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Students/Alumni, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Students/recruitment, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Students/Student Handbook, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Synagogues, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Synagogues/Synagogue Advisory Committee, undated (Box 5)
  - Midrasha/Yearbook, undated (Box 5)
- Series VII: Talmud Torah; General Education
  - Talmud Torah material is related to various "religious" or "Hebrew" schools that existed in Hartford in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. The early Talmud Torah's generally existed independently of any one synagogue. After the middle of the twentieth century, individual synagogues usually sponsored their own Hebrew schools. Today the type of religious education offered in these schools is usually called "Jewish Education.", undated (Box 7)
  - The General Jewish Education collection consists of material documenting broad educational concerns rather than specific organizations., undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/Garden Street Talmud Torah, undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/Nelson Street Talmud Torah, undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/Nelson Street Talmud Torah/auxiliary/Ledger, 1939-1943 (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/Nelson Street/Staff/Kriwitzky, Aaron/Bar Mizvah Talk, in Hebrew or Yiddish, undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/New Britain Talmud Torah, undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/Pleasant Street, undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/South End Talmud Torah, undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/Taslit's Hebrew School, undated (Box 7)
  - Talmud Torah/exhibit panels from Days of The Talmud Torah by Edith Gittleman and Fran Waltman, 1997, 3 oversize boxes, undated (Box 7)
  - General/Jewish Education council, undated (Box 7)
  - General/Jewish Information Series/National Jewish Welfare Board, undated (Box 7)
  - General/Miscellaneous, 2 folders, undated (Box 7)
  - General/National Organizations, undated (Box 7)
  - General/Newspaper clippings, 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 7)
  - General/Newspaper clippings, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 7)
  - General/Newspaper clippings, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 7)
  - General/Newspaper clippings, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 7)
  - General/Newspaper clippings, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 7)
  - General/Programs, undated (Box 7)
  - General/Research papers, undated (Box 7)
  - General/Synagogue Schools/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7)
- Series VIII: Public Education
  - Public Education/Arsenal School, Hartford, 1900s-1920s, 1900-1929 (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Barnard, Brown and Barnard-Brown Schools, Hartford, 1890s-1910s, 1890-1910 (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Frank O. Jones Junior High School, Hartford, 1930s, 1930-1939 (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Hall High School, West Hartford/RAR Fraternity/memorabilia, 1930s, 1930-1939 (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Hartford Public High School, 2 folders, undated (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Hartford Public High School/Newspapers/OVERSIZE, undated (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Northeast School, Hartford, 1930s-1940s, 1930-1949 (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Northwest School, Hartford, 1920s-1940s, 1920-1949 (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Vine Street School, Hartford, 1930s, 1930-1939 (Box 8)
  - Public Education/Weaver High School, Hartford, 2 folders. See also OVERSIZE, undated (Box 8)
  - Public Education/West Middle School, Hartford, 1920s, 1920-1929 (Box 8)
- Series IX: Higher Education, A-M
  - Beit Midrash, undated (Box 9)
  - Central Connecticut State University, undated (Box 9)
  - Connecticut College, undated (Box 9)
  - Greater Hartford Community College, undated (Box 9)
  - Hartford College for Women, undated (Box 9)
  - Hartford Hillel, undated (Box 9)
  - Hartford Institute for Jewish Studies, undated (Box 9)
  - Hartford Seminary, undated (Box 9)
  - Hartford Seminary/Zikmund Controversy, 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Hebrew Union College, undated (Box 9)
  - Hebrew University, undated (Box 9)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary, undated (Box 9)
  - Kadima High School/Beit Safer Tichon, undated (Box 9)
  - Miss Porter's School, undated (Box 9)
- Series X: Higher Education N-Z
  - Colleges/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10)
  - Technion, undated (Box 10)
  - Trinity College, undated (Box 10)
  - University of Connecticut, undated (Box 10)
  - Wesleyan Yale, undated (Box 10)
  - Yeshiva University, undated (Box 10)
- Series XI: Oversize
  - Public Education/Weaver High School, Hartford/Newspapers/OVERSIZE, undated
  - Hebrew School Notebook, 1940s, 1940-1949
- Series XII: Yearbooks
  Education; Hartford Public High School; Trinity College; Weaver High School; Yearbooks
  - Connecticut State Agricultural College, 1930
  - Connecticut State Agricultural College, 1930
  - Hartford Public High School, 1912
  - Hartford Public High School, 1915
  - Hartford Public High School, 1916
  - Hartford Public High School, 1920
  - Hartford Public High School, 1927 B
  - Hartford Public High School, 1928 B
  - Hartford Public High School, 1934 A
  - Hartford Public High School, 1936 B
  - Trinity College, 1933
  - Trinity College, 1934
  - Weaver High School, 1924
  - Weaver High School, 1924
  - Weaver High School, 1927 B
  - Weaver High School, 1931A
  - Weaver High School, 1932 B
  - Weaver High School, 1934A
  - Weaver High School, 1937
  - Weaver High School, 1939
    Harrington, Mildred K.
  - Weaver High School, 1940/Norman Lear, class of 1940
  - Weaver High School, 1941
  - Weaver High School, 1942
- Photo Series I: Education Photographs: A-M
  - Connecticut State Agricultural College, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Adult Education/Hebrew Institute for Jewish Studies, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Arsenal School, c.1900 (Box 1)
  - Barnard, Henry School, undated (Box 1)
  - Brown Street School Annex, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Bulkeley High School, early 20th, undated (Box 1)
  - Harris, Chauncy School OVERSIZE, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Hebrew School: see Talmud Torah, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Public High School, 1905 (Box 1)
  - Hartford Public High School, early 20th. See also oversize, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Public High School/clubs, early 20th, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Public High School/Athena Debating Club, c. 1920 (Box 1)
  - Hartford Public High School/Orchestra, early 20th, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Public High School/Sports, early 20th, undated (Box 1)
  - Hartford Public High School/OVERSIZE education photos, several, early 20th/sports/debating, undated
  - Hartford Talmud Torah, 1903/Rabbie David Traub's Cheder/Nettie Finkelstein, (Mrs. Samuel L. Goldman) only girl
  - Hartford Yeshiva/Hebrew Academy, undated
  - Hartford Yeshiva/Hebrew Academy/builidngs, undated
  - Hartford Yeshiva/Hebrew Academy/buildings/Gaster plaque dedication, 1992
  - Jones Junior High School, 1940s SUPER OVERSIZE. Copy, undated
  - Jones Junior High School, 1940s, undated
  - Maccabean Sunday School, 1918
  - Midrasha: filed here under M. Folders are labeled "Jewish Education/High Schools/Midrasha", undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Scholarships/Annie Fisher, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Activities, 1980s, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Choral Group, 1968-1969
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1968
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1969
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1970
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1971
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1972
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1973
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1974
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1975
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1976
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1977
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1978
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1979
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1980
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1981
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1983
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1984
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1986
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation, 1988
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Graduation/Display of work, 1971
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Holocaust Commemorations, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Jewish Art Classes, 1968-1969
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous, 1980s, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous, 1987
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous, 1990s, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Activities/Polaroid's, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Contact Sheets, 1980s, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Polaroid's, 1980s, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Polaroids, 1980s, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Slides, 1980s, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Miscellaneous/Students, undated
  - High Schools/Midrasha/Students, 1980s, undated
  - Miscellaneous Suburban Schools, 1915
  - Nelson Street Talmud Torah, 1934
  - New Britain Talmud Torah, c.1910
  - Second North District School Plaque, undated
  - Northeast Ladies Talmud Torah: see Nelson Street Talmud Torah, undated
  - Northeast School, 1920s, undated
- Photo Series II: Education Photographs: N-Z
  - Northwest School, 1920s, 1940s, undated
  - Pleasant Street Talmud Torah, 1914. The School was also known as Hartford Hebrew School., undated
  - Public Schools/Norwich/Ableman, Beatrice Evelyn, undated
  - Second North District School, undated
  - Solomon Schechter Day School/building, 1985, undated
  - Solomon Schechter Day School/Board, 1990s, undated
  - Solomon Schechter Day School/Students and activities, undated
  - Taslitt's Hebrew School, 1930s, undated
  - Second North School/Henry Barnard School, 1912, undated
  - Trinity College, 1920s, undated
  - United Conservative Religious School, 1980s, undated
  - Vine Street school: see also Weaver High School1941, undated
  - Wadsworth School OVERSIZE, undated
  - Weaver High School, reunion of class of 1948 in 1982, undated
  - Weaver High School 35th reunion, class of 1940 in 1975, undated
  - Weaver High School, 1941: Seymour Gold, Edwin Stolz, Dick Berenson, ? Winnick, Bob Yellin, see also Vine Street School, undated
  - Weaver High School/class of 1932 50th reunion, 1982 OVERSIZE, undated